Inputsstress tensor sigma1, sigma2, sigma3; all in MPa, +ve for compression trend and plunge of sigma1; trend of sigma3; all in degrees (pore fluid pressure required for opening angle, in MPa) poles to specific fracturesASCII text file, tab-delimited, with one pole per line as ‘plunge<tab>plunge direction’; all in degrees coefficient of friction & cohesive strength (MPa)(only for fracture susceptibility calculation) Outputs equal area stereograms (and optional Mohr diagrams) of normalised slip tendency (Ts), dilatation tendency (Td), fracture susceptibility (Sf) and opening angle (degrees) for all directions; plotted as MATLAB figures, and saved as 600 dpi TIFF, in the pattern ‘FracTend_*.tif’ASCII tab-delimited text file of poles to input fractures, with specific values of Ts, Td, Sf and OA, one set of values per line; saved as ‘PolesWithValues.txt’Operation copy all the files to a folderstart MATLABset the working folder to the folder with the code files in place any input data files in the same folder at the MATLAB prompt, type ‘guiFracTend’ and hit Enteruse the GUI window to select inputs and outputs click Run to generate ouptut plots please report any/all bugs to d.healy@abdn.ac.ukAcknowledgementsWe have used the following published code in FracTend:cmocean.m – uniform colorbarsThyng, K.M., Greene, C.A., Hetland, R.D., Zimmerle, H.M. and DiMarco, S.F., 2016. True colors of oceanography: Guidelines for effective and accurate colormap selection. Oceanography, 29(3), pp.9-13.various routines for tensors and coordinate geometry Allmendinger, R.W., Cardozo, N. and Fisher, D.M., 2011. Structural geology algorithms: Vectors and tensors. Cambridge University Press.